# Jeff Villanueva

www.jeffvillanueva.com 407.414.5709/jeff@jeffvillanueva.com

10670 Windsor Place, Orlando, FL 32821

### Profile

Dedicated and award winning audio professional with proven experiences providing high quality audio to the TV, Film, and Recording industries through audio post production and original recordings. Able to demonstrate the ability to work well in an intense team environment, which demands dedication, loyalty and adaptability by possessing the ability to stay highly self-motivated and able to motivate others by conveying ideas within a group or public setting.

#### Core Competencies include:

- Proven track record and strong reputation in the industry and with clients
- Extensive knowledge and skilled in all facets of production from: Recording, Mixing, Sound Design, Voice-Overs, and Foley
- Experience of using a variety of relevant DAW's and software packages Combined with analogue /digital gear for professional sounding results
- Desire to mentor and motivate others
- Demonstrate ability to effectively communicate both verbally and in writing
- Strong work ethic, raw ability and attention to detail
- Strong artistic and creative sensibilities

### Experience

#### Electronic Arts (EA) - Orlando, FL

Associate Producer of Talent / Recording Sessions

- In studio direction and coaching of commentary talent
- Detects any vocal anomalies during the session that will compromise signal chain/work with recording engineer to correct
- Is able to align talent with the creative vision while fostering an energetic and fun atmosphere for talent work in and ensuring talent's voices are not being overused by making the call to reschedule
- Follows up post session with design/production team to communicate content recorded
- Keeping a strict schedule to capture the required content defined
- Drive quality of recordings in alignment with scripts

#### Los Angeles Film School – Orlando, FL

Adjunct Course Director for Intro to The Music Industry – Online

October 2017 - Present

July 2018 - Present

- Create learning activities, including assignments, tests, quizzes and labs, and assess student outcomes in a timely manner through effective assessment and feedback practices.
- Create an environment of learning through effective teaching skills, maintain student-centered focus, and update curriculum to keep current and relevant to industry standards.
- Interact positively with diverse student populations; provide all students with equal opportunities for learning.

#### Full Sail University – Orlando, FL

Music Production Career Advisor

June 2014 - October 2017

- Educate and assist candidate graduates with career search practices, including: presentation skills, conducting research, resume review, cover letter writing, developing telephone and interviewing skills, and industry etiquette and responsibilities.
- Host industry guest and attend industry-related events and presentations.
- Provide accurate statistical information for the yearly accreditation.

### Wright Entertainment Group / Pop Nation Records – Orlando, FL

Mixing Engineer

• Gathering all of the recorded elements, assemble them, edit the performance, and provide equalization, effects, volume balance consistency, and maximization of critical performance traits to produce a polished final product.

• Effectively communicate and execute the vision for the final product from all of content creators involved collectively.

### Bad Boy Entertainment / 20th Anniversary Reunion Tour

Playback Technician

August 2016 - October 2016

August 2014 - March 2017

- Responsible for accurately cueing, playing and mixing pre-recorded sound elements for synchronized performance
- Takes directions and cues from the Musical Director or Stage Manager and must communicate with the performers.
- Familiar with the operations (signal pathways and connections) of a standard multi channel mixing board.

# Experience (Cont.)

#### DJ Khaled - We The Best Music Group / Track N' Field Entertainment - Miami, FL

May 2007 - June 2014

Studio Audio Director / Chief Engineer

- Represent the interests, concerns and problems of the studio and ensure issues are addressed and resolved expeditiously.
- Provide a creative, innovative and nurturing environment through the studio by developing an effective coaching/mentoring program that improve individual technical / professional skills.
- Work with talent, producers, directors and internal staff in a collaborative team environment to meet production deadlines.

#### Producer Rodney Jerkins - Dark Child Entertainment - Los Angeles, CA

May 2002 - May 2007

Chief Recording / Mixing Engineer

- Worked closely along side American record producer and songwriter collaborating with a broad range of popular artists.
- Set-up, record, edit, build/mix, and process audio productions using Various DAW's and production standards
- Work with talent, producers, directors and internal staff in a collaborative team environment to meet production deadlines.

#### Full Sail University – Winter Park, FL

June 2001- May 2002

Lab Instructor for Audio Post Production

- Utilize a variety of hands on teaching strategies in the process of creating a soundtrack to picture. Practices include: Production Dialogue Editing, ADR, Sound effects editing and design, Foley, Music Editing, and Mixing.
- Create an environment of learning through effective teaching skills, maintain student-centered focus, and update curriculum to keep current and relevant to industry standards.
- Interact positively with diverse student populations; provide all students with equal opportunities for learning.

#### Next Level Studios - Orlando, FL

November 1999 - December 2001

Owner / Chief Recording / Mixing Engineer

- Directing and providing leadership for activities in a studio including, but not limited to, all business, staff and financial operations, project profitability, marketing/business development, client satisfaction and employee growth and development
- Responsible for overall management of a studio (25-30 people).
- Monitor and evaluate the efficiency and effectiveness of the studio relating to all staff, business and financial operations.

#### Crawford Communications - Atlanta, GA

October 1998 - December 1999

Sound Editor

- Enhance, synchronize and equalize prerecorded dialogue, music, and sound effects with visual action of motion pictures or television productions.
- Helped business owners and radio stations establish brand familiarity thru unique and enhanced sonic branding by creating voiceovers, filler compositions including sweepers, promos, and jingles.

# Awards & Recognitions

The Recording Academy Grammy Awards

- 2011 Best Contemporary R&B Album for Usher "Raymond V Raymond"
- 2007 Best Contemporary R&B Album for Beyoncé "B Day"
- 2007 Best R&B Album for Mary J. Blige "The Breakthrough"
- 2006 Best Contemporary R&B Album for Mariah Carey "The Emancipation of Mimi"

### Publications

Blog From: ModernMixing.com | July 27, 2013 Psychology of a Mix Engineer: Jeff "Supa Jeff" Villanueva

Blog from: iStandardProducers.com | March 1, 2008 - Jeff Villanueva: Running' with The Runners

Article from: Mix Magazine | December 1, 2004 - "Engineer Jeff Villanueva on Working With Rodney Jerkins"

Article from: Remix Magazine | May 1, 2003 - " Talk About Pop Music" Jenny from Da Block

# Professional Affiliations

The Recording Academy (NARAS) – Voting Member for the Grammy Awards

# Education

Full Sail University – Winter Park, FL

Associate of Science Degree In Recording Arts & Sciences

October 1998